Okay, so in this section then, we are going
to talk about two important artifacts.
We're going to be talking
about the requirements
documentation and the
requirements traceability matrix.
So these are two very, very important
documents or artifacts, right,
and in the old PIMBox 6
terminology, they were referred
to as outputs of the requirements
management process.
They were outputs of collect requirements.
So let's talk about each of these then.
So the first document here then,
the requirements document, right?
Requirements documentation.
Remember, a requirement is what we are
going to be delivering, what the customer
wants, what the customer needs,
what is the end product or service,
whatever it is that we are delivering.
And again, the official definition,
right?
It's what is to be delivered
and the agreed upon capability
or condition of the product,
right, service or result.
So that is a requirement.
And there are many, many types of
requirements.
And exactly what kind of
requirements you need for
your project is going to be
dependent by the industry.
It's going to be dependent by the
organization.
The main requirement is a product
requirement.
This is what we are delivering.
This is what we need to build.
Right, that's going to be the main
requirement.
And again, that's going to be industry
specific.
But there's other types of requirements as
well.
You've got something called the business
requirements.
Well, what does the business need?
It's an internal project.
You're doing a project and there's several
business units involved.
Well, what are their requirements?
Right.
Stakeholder requirements.
What does a stakeholder need?
What does a stakeholder want?
You've got something called the solution
requirements.
Down here we have something called
non-functional requirements.
Non-functional requirements would be
things like training requirements.
for example, we're building this product
and, you know, whether it's a system,
an IT system, or whether it's a machine,
end users need training.
So what are the training requirements?
What are the safety requirements for the
use of this machine?
Safety requirements
for the person actually
using it and then for
people around that machine.
So that's a type of requirement as well.
Requirements related to security as well.
And what are all the security
requirements, protection from security
risk, confidentiality of information,
right?
If you're delivering a
system, an IT system,
well, when is it going to be available?
What happens if that system goes down?
How quickly does it need to be restored?
What's the continuity
of this system, right, in
case of disaster recovery
and so on and so forth?
So these would all be things like
non-functional requirements.
And plus you've got things
like transition requirements,
transitioning from the current
system to deployment to go live.
What are the requirements for that?
You have the old system that needs to be
sunset.
Now you've got the new system that's going
to be taking over.
So what's the transition requirements for
that?
We've also got requirements related to
quality.
That is a very important set of requirements,
very, very vital set of requirements.
There's a completely separate section in
quality and on quality management.
But what are the quality requirements for
this project?
and for this product.
Are we meeting ISO standards?
Are we meeting Six Sigma standards?
What are the requirements for that?
Plus regulatory requirements?
Just think of something simple when you're
building a house.
You're not just slapping pieces of wood
together and bricks
together to build a house.
The house has to meet building codes.
There are building standards, building
codes for everything related to the house,
plumbing, electric and the furnace and so
on and so forth.
and also foundations and everything has to
meet a certain building code requirement.
So what are the requirements for that?
What are the building codes?
Those are separate requirements as well.
So there are many, many types of
requirements.
And so those are all documented in the
requirements document.
And again, like I said,
there's not just going to be one
or not necessarily going to
be one requirement document.
There might be many requirement documents.
based on all these different types of
requirements.
So these are just a handful that I
mentioned, right?
Based on the industry, there may
be many, many more requirements
as well or many, many more
different types of requirements.
Now, the other important artifact is this
one called the traceability matrix,
requirements traceability matrix.
And what are requirements traceability
matrix is, it's just basically a grid.
It's usually nothing more than a
spreadsheet.
And it's making sure, again, that we are
doing all the work necessary and only the
work necessary to deliver the product,
right?
So we're not doing anything additional.
And basically what it's doing is every
activity is time back to a requirement and
every requirement is time back to a
business need.
So if we have an activity that's planned
and it's not time back to a requirement,
then the question is, why do we have this
activity, right?
That might identify some scope creep or
gold plating or something.
something going on.
It's also making sure then
we have our requirements,
we have enough activities
to meet those requirements.
Do we have enough activities to meet those
requirements?
Enough configuration
activities or enough testing
activities, right, enough
construction activities, right?
Whatever activities need to be done in
order to fulfill this requirement,
do we have enough?
Right.
So that is what the traceability matrix is
going to be documenting.
So it's basically document, as I said,
it's just a grid, right?
It's just basically a spreadsheet,
trace the requirements and the
deliverables back to the objective and the
business need.
Do we have enough requirements to meet the
business need?
And do we have enough activities to meet
the requirements?
If we've got additional activities,
that's not meeting the requirement,
I might expose some scope, creep,
goal plating, something going on.
We use this also to develop test
strategies and test scenarios.
we will often use that to develop test
scenarios because we want to make sure we
have enough activities to meet the
requirements.
Some of those activities are going to
involve testing.
We have enough testing activities to meet
those requirements.
And so it's also making sure that
requirements are not missed.
We have these requirements.
Do we have enough activities to meet these
requirements?
Making sure then the customer's needs
being fulfilled.
Make sure we're delivering what the
customer wants.
We are delivering what is required of the
project.
And making sure then deliverables are
being tested.
So that's the purpose then of the
traceability matrix.
So these are two very
important artifacts and
they're considered
outputs of the requirements.
And so again, these are two very important
artifacts, right?
The requirements documentation and
requirements traceability matrix,
and both of these are outputs of the
collect requirements process.